衝擊！
酷美身上到底
發生了什麼事！！
■
森 五郎（14）
不要問我 — 我什麼都沒看見
Don't ask me -- I didn't see nothing,
井出突然就發神經 然後做了不知道什麼事
'cause Ide was the one who went off on his own and did whatever it is he did.
雲雀弄 雛繪
■
衝擊！
酷美身上到底
發生了什麼事！！
■
她從沙灘回來的時候 我可擔心了
When she came back from the beach, I was worried,
因為她很久都昏迷不醒
because she was unconscious for so long.
但是她醒來後 突然變得活潑開朗
But as soon as she woke up, she was suddenly all perky and happy.
這一定是因為她感受到我對她的愛了
I think it's because she could sense my love for her.
這是頭一次 我覺得自己像是她的母親了
And now, for the first time ever, I actually feel like her mom.
大豆商店街
直升機 直升機！
Whoa! There's a chopper, a chopper!
世界要顛倒了！
The world is turning upside down!
春原 晴子（16）
■
氣死我了！受不了！
I'm so pissed off I can't stand it!
都怪那個混蛋耳機！
And it's all 'cause of those piece-of-shit headphones!
茱莉亞·仁由（?）
■
衝擊！
酷美身上到底
發生了什麼事！！
■
這是 Medical Mechanica 採取的緊急措施
It's an emergency measure put in place by Medical Mechanica.
人格的改變應該是其副作用
The change in personality is mostly likely a side effect.
哦！熨斗！
Oh! The Iron!
也被稱為熨平世界的機器
Also known as the World Smoother!
馬可 野方（14）
■
衝擊！
酷美身上到底
發生了什麼事！！
■
實話說 我確實覺得她挺可愛的
Well, to be honest, I do think she's pretty cute.
井出 交（14）
■
衝擊！
酷美身上到底
發生了什麼事！！
■
那個女孩…
That girl...
她不是雲雀弄
it's not Hibajiri.
晨安！同窗們！
Mm, top of the morning, fellow classmates!
酷美來了！亮閃閃 早早的
Hidomi is here, bright and early!
她好可愛
She's so cute.
ラリルレ
LOOPQR
晴子老師 求求你 做點什麼吧
Ms. Haruko, do something, I beg you!
都是你的錯 你沒有像我說的那樣摘下耳機
It's your fault. You didn't take off those headphones like I asked you.
我很抱歉！
And I'm really sorry about that!
時間寶貴 你卻在耽誤時間
You're wasting precious time that we don't have.
你知道你需要做什麼 所以趕快行動
You know what you need to do, so do it.
-你喜歡這樣打扮成女僕嗎？-Medical Mechanica
-Do you enjoy dressing up like a maid? -Medical Mechanica.
在那裡才能移除耳機
That's where we can remove them.
然後我們才能去追尋他
And then you and I can chase after him.
我們沒有別的選項
We don't have any other options.
希望不要遲到！
Hope I'm not late for work!
啊 痛
Ugh. That hurt.
雲雀弄
Hibajiri!
你在做什麼？
What are you doing?
畫好了！
It's all done!
用一個字來說 這是一首歌！
In a single word, this is a song!
-一首歌？-對的！
-A song? -That's right-o!
宇宙裡沒有氧氣 所以誰也聽不見你唱歌！
There's no oxygen in space, so no one can hear you sing!
但是星星轉啊轉啊轉 它們齊聲歌唱！
But the stars spin and spin and they spin around and around and they sing together!
星星的音樂？
The music of the stars?
啊！我的工作！
Oh, my job!
啊 好棒！他們要安裝一個新的設施！
Oh, cool! They're putting in a new ride!
讚！
Awesome!
時間到了 付錢吧
Your time is up. You need to pay me now.
好的
Sure.
合作愉快 拿著
Nice doing business. Here.
-我買了這個嗎？-正是如此 那麼
-Did I just buy this? -Precisely. Well...
下次服務見
Till the next time you need my services.
-那是什麼？-就是個海盜船唄
-What is that? -It's just a Viking ship.
好遜 我們回家吧
That's lame. Let's go home.
對不起 我遲到了
Sorry I'm late.
我很高興你來了
Oh, I'm just glad you made it.
那是什麼 屯吉先生？
What's that, Mr. Tonkichi?
這個嗎？
Hmm? This?
這是我們新的遊樂項目
It's about to be our new main attraction.
你找不到它了？
You can't find it?
別像個小孩一樣 趕快去找
Well, stop acting like a child and look for it.
我已經到處都找過了 就是找不到！
I already looked everywhere for it, but it's nowhere to be found!
那麼大的一個花盆 你居然也能搞丟了
Who in the hell loses something as big as a flower pot?
你就不能重新做一個嗎？
Can't you just make another one?
這是用這傢伙的部件造出來的獨一無二之物
It's a one-of-a-kind thing made from this guy's parts.
以我們的科技 不可能從零開始製作出來的
There's no way we can make another one from scratch, not with our technology.
天啊
Oh, man.
對了 你有沒有看到這裡放著的那個熊雕？
Oh, by the way, have you seen a carved bear that used to be here?
你真是…算了
You're such a... That's not important.
我回來了 伙伴們
I'm home, homeys.
重要的是那個花盆
The important thing is the flower pot.
我們要用它來監視… -是的我知道
We're supposed to use it to monitor -Yeah, I know.
我們要逆轉 N.O. 的流動
We want to reverse the current of the N.O.
如果我們假設 N.O. 是可以吸引物體的力量 那麼…
If we hypothesize that N.O. is a power that can pull objects from elsewhere, then --
我明白 那麼我們應該能夠逆轉它的方向
I see. Then it stands to reason we should be able to reverse the direction.
沒錯 然後
That's right. And... Mm!
1，2 出拳！現在 逆轉順序！
1, 2, punch it! Now, reverse the flow!
你們在幹什麼？
What are you guys doing?
嘿 愛子 歡迎回來
Oh, hey, Aiko. Welcome home.
哦 看啊 你很有潛力！
Oh! Look at that! You've got what it takes!
這拳頭真不錯！啊！
Those are amazing fists you have! Ah!
你又讓這個到處物色冠軍的傢伙到我們家裡來了？
You let the champion guy inside the house again?
你覺得如何？
What do you say?
我們倆可以站在世界巔峰—
You and I could take over the world!
她的拳頭像流星一樣！
This girl packs a punch like a shooting star!
鄰居們都在議論為什麼有一個怪異的流浪漢經常到我們家來
The neighbors are already whispering about why a weird homeless dude is always visiting our place.
我很抱歉 -你爸沒有做錯什麼
I'm so sorry. -Your dad has done no wrong, girl.
你爸是一個冠軍
Your dad's a champ.
大豆遊樂園
入場券
你原諒我們的話 我就給你這個
I'll give you these, if you forgive us.
你老是用這些免費門票來道歉
You're always pushing these comp tickets on me as reparations.
這些票到底是從哪裡來的？
Where the hell are you getting them from?
呃那個…
Oh, well, uh...
關於這個…
About that...
比起這個 我更想要 SPA 或者度假地的通票
I'd rather have a day pass to the spa or some resort.
我知道遊樂園增添了新的設施
I know the amusement park got a brand-new ride,
但不過是個無聊的海盜船罷了
but it turns out, it's just a lame Viking ship.
真的裝了?
It was installed?!
確定是海盜船嗎？！-對啊
It was the Viking ship?! You're sure?! -Uh, yeah.
他們做到了
Hey. They did it.
是的
That's right.
這對我們將是個大問題
This is gonna be a real issue for us.
你們在講些什麼呢 -喂 愛子
What are you talking about? -Oh, hey, Aiko?
你知道那個熊雕到哪裡去了嗎？
Do you know where the carved bear is?
你能來做測試運行的小白鼠 我真是很感激
I really appreciate you being the guinea pig for our test run.
沒關係 這是工作的內容
It's okay. It's part of the job.
真是個好小伙子
I just love what a good sport you always are.
以及 做這個是有額外獎金的對吧？
Besides, I get bonus pay for this, right?
沒錯 你需要錢嗎？
That's right. You need the money? Huh?
我…
Well, uh...
我想要買一個禮物
I-I wanted to buy a gift.
夢 是夢！
A dream. A dream!
我們為什麼要做夢？！
What is the reason we dream?!
難道只是因為它被稱作為夢？
Could it be because it is called a dream?!
有睡覺時做的夢 也有醒著的時候做的夢
There are dreams while we sleep and dreams while we're awake!
我們睡覺或者醒著都會做夢
We dream whether we're sleeping or awake!
我夢到一個夢！我夢見自己從夢裡醒來！
I have a dream! I dreamed that I woke up in a dream!
我們走
Let's go.
看這裡
Look here.
讓酷美恢復正常大作戰!!
■
耳機是沒有辦法移除的
Those headphones are going to be impossible to remove.
它們鑽入酷美的頭部已經太深了
They're too deep inside Hidomi's head.
她之所以行為異常
The reason why she's acting this way is because
是因為耳機從 Medical Mechanica 接收奇怪的電波
the headphones are receiving bizarre radiowaves from Medical Mechanica.
奇怪的電波！
Bizarre radiowaves!
要讓她恢復正常
To get her back to normal,
我們必須同時摧毀接收器和發射源
we need to simultaneously destroy the receptor and the transmission source.
計劃是這樣的 我們分成兩組行動
Here's the plan -- We'll split into two groups.
這樣我們可以分別攻擊工廠的內側和外側
That way, we can attack the Plant from the inside and outside.
拉哈路 你負責摧毀外部天線
Raharu, you will destroy the outer antenna.
好好
Aye-aye.
我要和酷美一起潛入 摧毀設施的內部
I will sneak in with Hidomi, destroy the facility inside,
最後解開耳機
and lastly, unlock the headphones.
喂 那是我的工作才對
Hey! But that should be my job!
我絕不允許你和酷美呆在一起
There's no way I am leaving Hidomi alone with you!
什什什麼 等一下！
W-W-What, what? Uh, wait a second!
我呢？
W-What about me?!
雲—雀—弄！
Hi--ba--ji--ri--!
我是酷美！我在這！
That's me! Hidomi!
那麼開始吧
Here we go!
啊啊啊！不不不不！
Aaaaaah! No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
真是個好小伙子
What a good sport he is.
該進去了 -但是怎麼進去？
Time to go in.  -But from where?
你告訴我
You tell me.
你連個計劃都沒有就好意思使喚我們？
You don't have a plan and you're bossing us around?!
不管你願不願意 我們只能一起想辦法
We have to figure this out together, whether you like it or not!
現在 合作一點！
Now, be useful!
閉嘴！少來指揮我！
Shut up! I don't take orders!
真是沒救了
We're getting nowhere.
這個寶物是個什麼？
What is this treasure?!
那個是森的女朋友的東西
Hmm? Oh. That's Mori's girlfriend's.
還是別動它
Best not touch it.
她花了很高的價錢買的
She paid a really high price for it.
很高？
Really high?
很高！
Really high!
你幹什麼呢？
What the hell are you doing?!
你怎麼就不明白？！
Why can't you just get it?!
它…它不想要你！
It doesn't... It doesn't want you!
你做了什麼？
What did you do?!
井出你這個蠢貨 因為你盡做蠢事—
Ide! You're an idiot, 'cause you do idiotic thin....
我們必須這麼做 因為這是證據
We have to do this, because it's evidence.
但是我也感到內疚
But I do feel a bit bad.
是啊
Yeah.
因為有這個傢伙
Because of this guy here,
我們的研究才能有這麼大的進展
our research made a lot of progress.
這麼說更準確 是因為這個傢伙留下的空殼
Or rather because of the shell that's left of him, anyway.
沒錯
So true.
這個空殼的主人不是一個生物
The owner of the shell isn't a living creature,
至少在我們的語義中 不算是生物
at least, not in our sense of the words.
好像是在生物和星球之間的某種巨大存在
It's almost like a larger being that's between a living creature and a planet.
那個星球可夠大的
The planet's quite big.
這就是為什麼它的週期有數年之久
And that's why its cycle lasts years at a time.
怎麼了？
What is it?
是花盆！
It's the flower pot!
你搞丟的那個花盆嗎？-它動了
You mean, the one that you lost? -It's moving.
那個東西只有對 N.O. 才會有反應
And that thing only activates in reaction to N.O.!
說明 N.O. 通道打開了
That means the N.O. must be open.
他們居然得到了花盆
They've actually got ahold of the flower pot.
而且流動逆轉了！
And it's in reverse flow!
好奇怪
That's weird.
他們被吸進你的腦袋裡了
They went inside your head! Bicu-bicu!
雲雀弄 你到底怎麼了？
Hibajiri... What exactly happened to you?
你會永遠這個樣子嗎？
And are you gonna stay this hyper forever?
嗯？你什麼意思？我一直是這樣
Hmm? What do you mean? I've always been like this.
蛤？一直？
Huh? Always?
實話說…
To be honest...
從我記事起就是這樣
as long as I can remember.
等等等等等等等等！啊—！
Wait, wait, wait! Wait, wait, wait, wait! Wait! Aaaaaah!
你能不能閉嘴？囉嗦死了！
Will you shut up? You're such a broken record!
你為什麼不明白？
Why can't you understand?!
這不是他想要的
That is not what he wants, all right?
好像你很懂他一樣 真是好笑
Funny how you seem to think you know him so well.
我懂他
Well, I do.
你再說一遍 我就殺了你
If you say that again, I'm gonna kill you.
他需要自由
He needs to have his freedom.
任何想要拘束他的人都是我的敵人
Anyone who tries to keep him tied down is my enemy.
不管是 Medical Mechanica…
Medical Mechanica...
還是你
and even you.
他…
He just...
閉嘴
Shut up!
我受夠了你談論他
I'm sick of hearing you talk about him!
我想要什麼 就會去得到它
When I want something, I get it!
只要能讓他看見我 我會做任何事情
I'll do what I need to make sure he sees me!
你不會成功的
You're going to fail.
我全都理解
I understand everything.
我理解他
I understand him.
也理解你
And you, too.
你真敢說啊
How dare you say that.
我會一直說
I will keep on saying it!
你必須與我同心
You need to join me, Raharu!
畢竟 你就是我
You're me, after all!
好啊
Fine!
拉哈路
Raharu...
你終於明白了
you finally get it.
我們一起的話 一定可以…
Together, I know we can --
我要吞噬你
I am gonna devour you.
雲雀弄？
Hibajiri?!
你在哪 雲雀弄？
Where are you, Hibajiri?!
雲雀弄！
Hibajiri!
小心！雲雀弄！
Hibajiri! W-Watch out!
視野真好！
I can see everything!
我的父親在哪裡
Where is, どこですか, my father?!
啊 我把這個給忘了
Oh, yeah. I forgot about that.
你沒有父親的
You don't have a father, huh?
我也沒有母親
I don't have a mother, either.
什麼？
What?
媽媽已經等了很久了
Mommy's been waiting a long time,
但是他還是不回家！
but he still won't come home!
雲雀弄…
Hibajiri...
如果一切都被毀掉 我們就能重新開始
If everything's destroyed, then we can start over again.
至少媽媽不會再傷心
For one, Mom would no longer be crushed.
而且爸爸會和我們在一起
And also, Dad would still be with us.
如果今天和昨天一樣 是平凡的一天 那樣該有多好！
If today was an ordinary day, like yesterday, that would've been, oh, so nice!
雲雀弄！
Hibajiri!
天啊 差一點
Oh, man, that was close.
我不需要什麼特別的東西
I don't need anything special.
但是憤怒 悲傷 啜泣和哭喊
But the anger, the sadness, the sobbing and crying,
我不想再聽到了
I don't want to hear it anymore.
所以
And so...
這就是為什麼這副耳機正適合我
that's why these are perfect.
住手！拉哈路！
Stop it! Raharu!
雲雀弄 我—
Hibajiri, I --
怎麼回事？
What happened?
雲雀弄！雲雀弄！
Hibajiri? Hibajiri!
怎麼回事？
What's going on?!
雲雀弄！
Hibajiri!
你怎麼了？！
What's wrong?!
喂 回答我！
Hey, answer me!
那副耳機
The headphones.
雲雀弄？
Huh? Hibajiri?
你恢復正常了？
Are you back to normal?
井出
Oh, Ide.
喂
Whoa. Hey.
我 我要溢出來了
I-I think I'm going to overflow.
蛤？-我要溢出來了！
Huh? I'm going to overflow!
我要…
I'm going to...
等等 那是什麼意思？
Wait. What does that mean?
我 我要溢出來了！-雲雀弄！
I'm going to overflow! -Hibajiri!
我要溢出來了！
I'm going to overflow!
什麼？！
What?!
世界… 要翻個底朝天了！
The world... is turning inside out!
那是？
What?
那是什麼？！
What was that?!
雲雀弄！
Hibajiri!
天啊 難以置信
Whoa. I don't believe it.
-難道是海盜王？-不是！
Is that the Pirate Ki--? -It's not!
但那力量確實是他的
But that power is.
開始了！
Uh, it's begun!
雲雀弄！
Hey, Hibajiri?!
現在又是什麼鬼！
What now?!
下面發生了什麼事？！
What is happening down there?!
這聲音 什麼在滾動？
What's that rolling sound?
雲雀弄！
Hibajiri!
停手！拉哈路！
Cut it out! Raharu!
閉嘴！
Shut up!
還有你的墨鏡很遜！
And your sunglasses are lame!
你怎麼敢？！
How dare you?!
雲雀弄！
Hibajiri!
混蛋！
てめぇ！
雲雀弄！
Hibajiri!
雲雀弄！太好了 你醒了！
Hibajiri?! Good, you woke up!
井出？！
Ide?!
雲雀弄！我來了！
Hibajiri! I'm coming!
放手吧 拉哈路！
Give up, Raharu!
雲雀弄！
Hibajiri!
井出！不！
Ide, no!
啊 再加把勁
Oh, come on!
天啊！對不起 我不是有意的
Oh, God! Uh, sorry, I didn't mean to.
但是沒時間說—啊啊！
But we don't have time to discu-- Aaaah!
酷美！
Hidomi!
仁由！
Jinyu!
你最好不要放鬆警惕！
You'd better not let your guard down!
住手 拉哈路！
Stop it, Raharu!
閉嘴 遜墨鏡！
Shut up, Lame Glasses!
你沒事吧？！
Are you okay?!
夠了！拉哈路！
That's enough! Raharu!
仁由！
Jinyu!
仁由？
Uh, Jinyu?
那那那個東西 要倒下來了！
T-T-That thing over there is falling!
喂 仁由？！
Hey, Jinyu?!
別！住手！
No! Don't!
工廠…
The Plant...
豎起來了？
Stood up?
仁由
Jinyu.
拉—拉哈路…
R-Raharu...
我只是想讓他獲得自由
I just wanted for him to have his freedom.
我愛他
I love him.
這就是我的理由
That's why.
我想讓他不受我們的拘束
I want him to be free from us.
你不明白喵
You don't get it, no.
一切都是屬於他的
Everything has always belonged to him,
從一開始就是如此
right from the very beginning.
他的鐐銬和他的自由
His shackles and his freedom.
這個世界裡沒有什麼是不屬於他的
There isn't anything in this world that doesn't belong to him.
沒有例外
Nothing.
這就解決了
That settles it.
所以我們到頭來還是不一樣
So we're not the same, after all.
我也這麼想
I guess so.
你也許是對的
Perhaps, you're right.
到我這裡來吧 仁由
Come with me, Jinyu.
我們終於可以到一起了
We can finally be together.
你也跟我來吧？怎麼樣？
Now, why don't you come with me, as well?
酷美？
Hidomi?
雲雀弄！
Hibajiri!
我明白了
I get it.
我終於明白了
I finally understand.
我知道你想要做什麼了
I know what you want to do.
所以…
And that's why...
我不能跟你走
I can't go with you.